♪If I am gone from this world,
will the dark night collapse?♪
♪If I never return
to guard by your side♪
♪If I seal away our encounter
and erase all trace♪
♪Like endless snow
falling into the deep sea♪
♪This life is but a fleeting illusion,
yet it gave me courage♪
♪Love is a miracle♪
=Spring Over Phoenix Pond=
(Adapted from Qin An'an's
"Spring Over Phoenix Pond")
=Episode 1=
Xiao Yunting, Prince Jing,
(Xiao Yunting, Prince Jing)
has rebelled to seize power.
By order of Prince Qi,
kill him immediately!
- Charge!
(Qi Yuan,)
(wait for me.)
(Yuan,)
(leaving you alone at the manor
on our wedding night was not my choice.)
(If Prince Qi succeeds
in usurping the throne,)
(the realm will never know peace.)
(Once I wipe out his faction,)
(I will honor my vow
to grow old with you.)
(Prince Qi)
Prince Qi?
Why are you here?
Prince Jing feared defeat,
so he handed you over to me
just to spare his own life.
Impossible.
Qi Yuan,
(Qi Yuan, true daughter of Marquis Yongping)
you have nowhere to run.
Just behave and stay by my side.
(Since there is no escape,)
(then let us die together.)
You actually dared to poison me?
Qi Yuan,
on the road to the underworld,
don't go too fast.
(I was supposed to be
a young lady of the Marquis Residence,)
(yet I was swapped and raised
as a rustic butcher's daughter.)
(Wicked people conspired
to ruin my reputation,)
(and my own family abandoned me,
leaving me adrift for half my life.)
Mother.
Mother!
(Fortunately, Xiao Yunting
saved me from the abyss.)
(He said)
(I was not only his hidden guard)
(but also his only light.)
(Yet on our wedding night,)
(he broke his oath,)
(sold his wife, and betrayed his word.)
(If there is a next life,)
(family,)
(love...)
(I want none of it.)
=Spring Over Phoenix Pond=
(I will raise a blade with my own hands)
(and slaughter
every fate this world has set.)
(Where am I?)
(This is the night
before I returned to the Qi Residence.)
(I didn't die.)
A noble lady who's lost her purity?
Let's see how you
return to the Marquis Residence
to steal Jin's wealth and status.
Butcher Xu,
she's the real young lady
of the Marquis Residence.
Are you really letting me
have my way with her?
Cut the chatter.
Just do as you're told.
Return to the Marquis Residence?
She doesn't have the fate for it.
So what if you're noble-born?
Aren't you still
mine to take?
(Ding Chengyong, local ruffian)
My eyes...
It was your foster parents,
Li Xiu
and Butcher Xu.
They wanted me to ruin your purity
so you couldn't return
to the Marquis Residence.
Jin is brilliant after all.
Now she can sleep easy
in the Marquis Residence.
Still, she's not my flesh
and blood either.
Should I also...
(Butcher Xu: Qi Yuan's adoptive father)
No.
Father.
Father, save me!
I am coming.
(Rakshasa Temple)
Listen up,
folks.
A ruined noble lady
ain't worth a thing.
Why don't we tie her up
and collect a reward from the Qi family?
- Yeah, let's collect the reward.
- Let's go get it.
Xiu, you've done us a huge favor.
How dare you...
Xiu!
Someone's dead!
What happened?
Let me go.
Let go of me!
You fools!
Li Xiu,
(Li Xiu, Qi Yuan's adoptive mother)
you committed adultery with Chengyong,
(Steward, manager of the Qi Estate)
and Butcher Xu caught you.
Butcher Xu and Ding Chengyong
got into a fight
in this Rakshasa Temple.
Young Lady Qi feared
something bad would happen
and sent me to mediate,
only to be framed by you.
You adulteress, how dare
you twist the truth like this!
No.
That's not how it happened.
Both Butcher Xu and Ding Chengyong's
bodies are right here.
And this.
(Xiu)
This was found in Ding Chengyong's home.
How are you going
to explain yourself, you adulteress?
Confess already.
Committing adultery
and causing human lives to be lost...
Heaven will not tolerate this.
Light the fire.
No.
- Kill her!
That's not true.
Everyone...
- Kill her!
Mr. Steward,
since she raised me,
please let me talk to
my mother for a moment.
How does it feel to have
your reputation ruined?
It really was you
who gave the undergarment
to Ding Chengyong.
Now you dare to frame me,
you jerk!
Eighteen years ago,
you used your role
as a wet nurse to swap the babies,
reducing me,
the true daughter, to this state.
Now that the Marquis Residence
has come looking for me,
you want to ruin my purity again.
You just want your fake daughter, Jin,
to sit comfortably in
the Marquis Residence without a worry.
If you dare to lay a finger on Jin,
I won't let you off even as a ghost.
I will kill you!
I'm already an evil ghost
that crawled out of the underworld.
This debt of blood...
We'll start
with your precious Jin.
You jerk!
I will kill you!
Mother,
please don't kill me.
Mother.
- Please...
- Jerk.
Jerk!
Mother,
I beg you.
Unrepentant till the end,
utterly malicious.
Execute.
No.
I'm innocent.
Jerk!
Just go to heck!
(Inner Manor of the Qi Residence,
Peaceful Residence)
- Welcome back, Young Lady.
(Heaven grants me
a second chance in this game.)
(This time, I will be the weiqi player,)
(not a pawn on the board.)
(Qi Jin, fake daughter
of Yongping Marquis)
So what if Qi Yuan has returned?
The Young Lady of the Qi family
can only be me.
Whoever blocks my path...
Whoever steals my position...
- Deities in my way will fall.
- Buddha in my way will fall.
♪How I wish to hold
onto this fleeting warmth♪
♪How I wish to live
this life only for you♪
♪When memories sink
and the heart settles♪
♪Forgetting life, death,
parting, and reunion♪
♪How I wish to stay
only in the moment with you♪
♪Anchoring myself by your side♪